Rollo ("Tug") Trout Simmons

356 E. Stadium Ave. Provo UT 84604 (385)-200-4403 tugwuzhere@gmail.com

Skills

I have extensive personal experience working with reptiles, amphibians, and invertebrates. I have over 50 of my own reptiles and amphibians, across 25 different species, and they have provided me with many insights into animal husbandry and care. I additionally have some limited experience with planted freshwater fish tanks, and have multiple aquatic species that are housed in planted aquariums, as well as a large freshwater community fish tank. I hold a deep love for wildlife, biodiversity, and conservation; few things bring me more joy than providing/caring for wildlife, whether it be observing wild animals, or caring for domestic/captive bred ones, or spreading educational awareness of the importance and wonder of wildlife, particularly herpetofauna and other often under-appreciated/overlooked groups of wildlife.

Experience

September 2015 - February 2016

Papa Murphys Pizza, Springville UT

- line chef

- Taking orders over the phone and at the register
- Making pizzas as well as sides at top efficiency on a line
- Dealing with upset and confused customers calling in for pizza cooking support
- Keeping food production areas clean and sanitized
- Taking inventory

January 2018 - February 2018

Vivint Smarthome (at home) - Customer Care Specialist

- Troubleshooting technical support for Vivint sensors and equipment
- Taking monthly bill payment phone calls and account support
- Assisting in calming down escalated customers
- (Left after short period on floor after training due to highly inadequate "training")

September 2019 - Spring 2022

Great Basin Serpentarium - Animal Care Intern/Volunteer Animal Caretaker

- Developed and currently overseeing a grasshopper breeding program and diapause research of the *M. differentialis* species for the purpose of production and sale within feeder insect markets intended for pet reptiles and amphibians.
- Managing 30+ breeding populations of *Blaptica dubia* for the purpose of producing feeder insects for pet reptiles and amphibians.

- Care for other invertebrates, as well as reptiles and amphibians
 - Cleaning cages
 - Feeding
 - Setup and management of other invertebrate breeding programs
- General care and overseeing of animals within the facility
- Experience working around dangerous and venomous species of reptiles, particularly illegally possessed rattlesnakes confiscated from citizens by law enforcement, as well as endangered desert tortoises similarly confiscated by law enforcement.

March 2022 - September 2022, April 2023 - September 2023

Environmental Resource Management (Camp Williams Utah National Guard Employee) – Seasonal Wildlife Technician (Herpetofauna Specialization)

- Twice Weekly telemetry tracking of 20+ individual Great Basin Rattlesnakes
- Direct interaction with rattlesnakes including but not limited to collection at den sites for
 processing and re-release, safe tube-enabled handling of rattlesnakes of all sizes, data
 collection, and removal from buildings occupied by soldiers or other individuals
- General herpetofauna processing, including but not limited to, pit-tagging, data collection, safe removal from in use buildings, physical handling for purposes of measuring weight, length, sex, etc. data of individual specimens of various snake species including Great Basin rattlesnakes, gopher snakes, and other herpetofauna.
- Ecological data surveying such as water conditions of streams, springs, and ponds
- Snake den data collection and surveys
- Assisted in medical operations to install telemetry tracking signal repeaters in rattlesnakes
- Worked with national guard to provide education and awareness to various NG-UT workers, employees, and stationed soldiers to promote awareness, safety, and appreciation around potentially dangerous herpetofauna
- Pitfall trap data collection and direct interaction with surveyed/captured individuals such as native species of rodents, lizards, and snakes
- Installation of pitfall traps and other ecological survey equipment
- Extensive experience outdoors in adverse conditions hiking long distances in high altitude desert situations
- Amphibian net-trap surveying and data collection
- Mist-net bat surveying done at various sites in late night conditions
- Analysis of wildlife cameras and sound-trap data to survey for native wildlife and estimate populations

October 2022 - January 2023

Loveland Living Planet Aquarium - *Public Programs Educator*

- On floor education and interaction with guests regarding aquarium wildlife
- Provided knowledge and presentations regarding charismatic wildlife on display,
 conservation practices and programs, and AZA facility procedures and regulations
- Day to day guest interaction through active engagement, answering questions, and helping
 design and administer specialized and thematic presentations designed around seasonal
 and targeted events.

Education

Springville High School - Graduated 2017

UVU -August 2018- Now

References

Chelsey Beck (FBLA, DACA, BLT advisor) 801-400-3505

Chris Frauenhofer (Wildlife Biologist stationed at Camp Williams, National Guard)

716-479-8839, cfrauenhofer@utah.gov

Dr. Joey Mugleston (Great Basin Serpentarium owner and overseer) 435-862-6500

 $Dr.\,Geoffrey\,Zahn\,(Research\,mentor\,on\,research\,conducted\,regarding\,Utah\,Lake's\,aquatic$

fungal communities) <u>10817462@uvu.edu</u>

Sierra Wood (Edu. Department assistant manager at Loveland Living Planet Aquarium)

434-221-3904, woodsierra1999@gmail.com